Edith A. Hadamard Travel Slide Collection
Yale University Arts Library
Edith A. Hadamard Travel Slide Collection
1950-1980
VRC 134
Yale University Arts Library
5.16
22 boxes in 4 containers
Collection of 1,803 briefly labeled 35 mm color slides taken in the 1950s-1970s on travels to the Mediterranean, Latin America, and in the United States. Mostly architectural photography, but also many market and street scenes in rural areas of Latin America.
Hadamard, Edith A.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Scope and Contents
Collection of 1,803 briefly labeled 35 mm color slides taken in the 1950s-1970s on travels to the Mediterranean, Latin America, and in the United States. Mostly architectural photography, but also many market and street scenes in rural areas of Latin America. These slides are of Classical, Byzantine, and Precolumbian sites, colonial, vernacular and modern architecture, general scenic/tourist views, and street markets.
Arrangement
Arranged by destination.
Travel photography; Slides; Reproductions
- These slides are of Classical, Byzantine, and Precolumbian sites, colonial, vernacular and modern architecture, general scenic/tourist views, and street markets.
- Greece (Box 1)
  General
  (81 slides) [Slide boxes1-4]
  - Miscellaneous (6 slides) (Box 1)
  - Athens (75 slides), both Classical and Byzantine sites (Box 1)
  - Corinth (16 slides) [Slide box 2] (Box 1)
  - Crete (13 slides) (Box 1)
  - Daphni (22 slides) (Box 1)
  - Delos (24 slides) (Box 1)
  - Delphi, 1964 and 1966 (12 slides) [Slide box 3] (Box 1)
  - Epidauros, 1966 (7 slides) (Box 1)
  - Hosios Lukas, 1966 (8 slides) (Box 1)
  - Lindos, Rhodes, 1966 (4 slides) (Box 1)
  - Mistra, 1964 and 1966 (14 slides) (Box 1)
  - Mycenae, 1964 (12 slides) (Box 1)
  - Mykonos, 1964 (24 slides) (Box 1)
  - Olympia, 1964 (14 slides) [Slide box 4] (Box 1)
  - Rhodes, 1964 and 1966 (36 slides) (Box 1)
  - Sounion, 1964 (5 slides) (Box 1)
- Turkey (Box 1)
  [Slide boxes 4-5]
  - Constantinople (Istanbul), 1964 (34 slides) (Box 1)
  - Ephesus, 1964 (13 slides) [Slide box 5] (Box 1)
- Spain (Box 1)
  - Seville, 1952 (4 slides) (Box 1)
  - Grenada, 1954 (48 slides) (Box 1)
- Algeria, 1969 (Box 1)
  (8 slides)
- France, 1951 (Box 1)
  (8 slides) [Slide box 6]
  - Arles (Box 1)
  - Carcassonne (Box 1)
  - S. Remy (Box 1)
- Italy (Box 1)
  - Rome, 1964 and 1966 (65 slides) (Box 1)
- Haiti (Box 2)
  [Slide box 7]
  - 1955 and 1956 (36 slides, including one of S. Bartholomew's) (Box 2)
- United States (Box 2)
  - Miscellaneous, 1965, 1967, 1971 (9 slides) (Box 2)
  - New York, 1951, 1955, 1968, 1976 (11 slides) (Box 2)
  - Niagara Falls, 1952 (8 slides) (Box 2)
  - Pittsburgh, 1966 (6 slides) (Box 2)
  - Williamsburg VA, 1954 (7 slides) (Box 2)
- Cuba (Box 2)
  [Slide box 8]
  - 1956 (9 slides) (Box 2)
- Canada (Box 2)
  - 1966 and 1970 (including Montreal Expo) (19 slides) (Box 2)
- Panama (Box 2)
  - 1969 (2 slides) (Box 2)
- Mexico (Box 2)
  [Slide boxes 8-19]
  - Miscellaneous, 1957-1959, 1962-1963, 1969 (40 slides) (Box 2)
  - Aquacatenango, 1959 (11 slides) (Box 2)
  - Chiapa de Corzo, 1959 (7 slides) [Slide box 9] (Box 2)
  - Chichicastenango, 1962 (23 slides) (Box 2)
  - Chichen Itza, 1959 (66 slides) (Box 2)
  - Chichen Itza, 1959 (continued) (26 slides) [Slide box 10] (Box 2)
  - Chilil, 1959 (15 slides) (Box 2)
  - Coyotapec, 1957 (7 slides) (Box 2)
  - Cuernavaca, 1956, 1969 (7 slides) (Box 2)
  - Guadalupe, 1956 (4 slides) (Box 2)
  - Guadalajara, 1958 (23 slides) (Box 2)
  - Guanajuato, 1958 (12 slides) [Slide box 11] (Box 2)
  - Janitzio, 1958 (14 slides) (Box 2)
  - Kabah, 1959 (1 slide) (Box 2)
  - La Venta, 1963 (13 slides) (Box 2)
  - Merida, 1964 (34 slides) (Box 2)
  - Mexico City, 1956, 1957, 1967, 1969 (126 slides) [Slide box 12-13] (Box 2–3)
  - Mitla, 1957 (19 slides) [Slide box 13] (Box 3)
  - Monte Alban, 1957 (18 slides) (Box 3)
  - Morelia, 1958 (10 slides) [Slide box 14] (Box 3)
  - Oaxaca, 1957 (30 slides) (Box 3)
  - Palenque, 1963 (27 slides, some credited to INAH) (Box 3)
  - Patzquaro, 1958 (15 slides) (Box 3)
  - Sayil, 1959 (10 slides) [Slide box 15] (Box 3)
  - S. Agustin de Acolman, 1956 (7 slides) (Box 3)
  - S. Cristobal, 1959 (32 slides) (Box 3)
  - S. Francisco el Alto, 1962 (12 slides) (Box 3)
  - S. Francisco el Alto, 1962 (12 slides) (Box 3)
  - S. Miguel Allende (continued), 1958 (14 slides) [Slide box 16] (Box 3)
  - Taxco, 1957, 1969 (70 slides) (Box 3)
  - Taxco (continued), 1957, 1969 (36 slides) [Slide box 17] (Box 3)
  - Teotihuacan, 1956, 1967, 1969 (26 slides) (Box 3)
  - Teotitlan del Valle, 1957 (11 slides) (Box 3)
  - Tlacochahuaya, 1957 (4 slides) (Box 3)
  - Tlacolula, 1957 (8 slides) (Box 3)
  - Tula, 1957 (2 slides) [Slide box 18] (Box 3)
  - Tulum, 1964 (21 slides) (Box 3)
  - Tzintzuntzan, 1958 (3 slides) (Box 3)
  - Uxmal, 1959 (33 slides) (Box 3)
  - Veracruz, 1959 (19 slides) (Box 3)
  - Xlapac, 1959 (5 slides) [Slide box 19] (Box 4)
  - Xochimilco, 1956 (9 slides) (Box 4)
  - Zinacantan, 1959 (9 slides) (Box 4)
- Guatemala (Box 4)
  - Miscellaneous, 1962 (9 slides) (Box 4)
  - Antigua, 1962 (29 slides) (Box 4)
  - Palim, 1962 (5 slides) (Box 4)
  - S. Antonio Aguas Calientes, 1962 (3 slides) (Box 4)
  - Sololá, 1962 (11 slides) (Box 4)
  - Tikal, 1962 (62 slides) [Slide box 20] (Box 4)
- Honduras (Box 4)
  - Copan, 1962 (19 slides) (Box 4)
- Painting (Box 4)
  (43 slides) [Slide box 21]
- Sculpture (Box 4)
  (143 slides) [Slide box 21-22]